

DEVOPS ENGINEER

Pacific Standard Time (UTC -8)

■ jesse.prieur@gmail.com | ★ jesseprieur.github.io/resume | ᡚ jesseprieur | the jesseprieur

Summary _

Innovative and creative software engineer with 7+ years of experience in DevOps. After transitioning from a general software development background, became a crucial team leader for creating, maintaining, and improving continuous integration and delivery platforms using a variety of languages, technologies, and applications.

</> Skills___

laC Chef, Terraform, Vagrant, Vault, PowerShell DSC

CI / CD Jenkins, GitHub Actions, BuildKite, Artifactory, GoCD

Cloud AWS, Azure, GCP

Containers Docker, OpenShift, Kubernetes

Programming Bash, PowerShell, Ruby, C# (.Net), Java, Go

Monitoring PRTG, Splunk

Work Experience _____

Levio (formerly Indellient)

Oakville, Canada

SENIOR SOLUTIONS ENGINEER

May 2021 - Present

- Used a multitude of technologies (including Chef, Terraform, Vault, AWS) on several clients of various sizes to design, create or update build, continuous integration, and continuous delivery systems with varying degrees of complexity.
- · Interacted with clients at the business and software engineering levels to determine where their build process was facing issues.
- · Created high- and low-level design diagrams and documentation explaining clients current pain points, and the recommendations to fix them.
- Helped with creating business milestones and customer success metrics, which would then translate over to development milestones, sprints and tickets
- Developed code to create or upgrade build systems which was well tested and verifiable using DevOps best practices and principles canary pipelines, blue/green deployments, least intrusive builds, etc.
- Had regular check in calls with clients to discuss progress, blockers and timeline.
- · Once development was complete, had hand off meetings and provided demos and documentation of all work done.
- Regularly communicated with clients after project completion to make sure that code was still working as expected.
- Mentored and assisted less experienced DevOps engineers both in company and working for clients.

Global Payments (formerly Cayan)

Boston, USA

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

Aug 2014 - May 2021

- Increased release cadence from biweekly to twice daily, through modifications and improvements to PowerShell, Chef, Hyper-V, and Failover Cluster commands and actions.
- Changed the Engineering Lab from one that was rigidly relying on an evaluation of SCVMM and had a single point of failure, to one that was easily able to recover from common error scenarios and in catastrophic cases, could be brought back up from scratch within 3 hours.
- Interviewed and trained two senior release engineers and a release engineer on the systems, as well as best practices and principles for DevOps.
- Was contacted by parent company to lead sibling companies towards Windows-based DevOps best practices, to present some of the experience I'd gained, and to show how we had accomplished certain automated tasks.
- Took lead on designing, creating a proof of concept, and implementing OpenStack, a private virtual cloud, inside our datacenter for our parent/sibling companies, which would allow each company portions of the datacenter, along with the tools needed to administer each of them adequately.
- Used Chef and Vagrant to create an laaS setup, which could be easily re-instantiated quickly.
- Designed and created a highly available and scalable reverse proxy system which helped other developers access different iterations and versions of our web applications quickly and easily through SNI, both for testing and verification.

Credit Suisse (via Infusion)

London, UK

.NET SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep 2012 - Aug 2014

- Designed, developed, tested and debugged a workflow-based application for improved EPE on defaults for the bank using Agile methodologies and following SOLID principles to create an architecturally strong and scalable application, from conception through to production.
- · Actively involved in code reviews, sprint retrospectives, library assessment meetings and daily standups for status reports and knowledge sharing.
- Improved coworkers and fellow teammates previously implemented code using proven coding practices MVVM, SOLID principles, TDD, Pair-Programming, and IoC.

March 24, 2023

Radix Windsor, Canada

Junior .Net Software Engineer Aug 2011 - Aug 2012

- Developed, maintained and debugged several database-heavy applications in C# WinForms, for many clients simultaneously.
- Experimented with different programming suites to find the best software to use with each project.
- Tasked with meeting clients, assessing their needs, developing a time schedule for release that was realistic and acceptable, and under certain circumstances developing quick demos onsite.
- Frequently gave feedback during several meetings regarding program requirements and feasibility.
- Built small code libraries for interacting with Serial Port based robotic equipment.

Certificates

Mar 2023 HashiCorp Certified: Vault Associate, HashiCorp

Nov 2021 HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate, HashiCorp

Jun 2021 Chef Principles Certificate, Progress Chef

Education _

University of Windsor Windsor, Canada

Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours)

Sep 2006 - May 2011

MARCH 24, 2023 2